{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Suppose the length of each side of a regular hexagon ABCDEF is 2 cm. If T is the mid-point of CD, then the length of AT, in cm, is:",
        "options": ["√12", "√15", "√14", "√13"],
        "answer": "√13"
      },
      {
        "question": "If r is a constant such that [x²-4x - 13] has exactly three distinct real roots, then the value of r is:",
        "options": ["17", "15", "21", "18"],
        "answer": "17"
      },
      {
        "question": "A basket of 2 apples, 4 oranges and 6 mangoes costs the same as a basket of 1 apple, 4 oranges and 8 mangoes, or a basket of 8 oranges and 7 mangoes. Then the number of mangoes in a basket of mangoes that has the same cost as the other baskets is:",
        "options": ["13", "10", "11", "12"],
        "answer": "13"
      },
      {
        "question": "Identical chocolate pieces are sold in boxes of two sizes, small and large. The large box is sold for twice the price of the small box. If the selling price per gram of chocolate in the large box is 12% less than that in the small box, then the percentage by which the weight of chocolate in the large box exceeds that in the small box is nearest to:",
        "options": ["124", "135", "144", "127"],
        "answer": "127"
      },
      {
        "question": "If x₀ = 1, x₁ = 2, and xₙ₊₂= 1 + xₙ₊₁ / xₙ ,n = 0, 1, 2, 3, ..., then x₂₀₂₁ is equal to:",
        "options": ["4", "2", "3", "1"],
        "answer": "2"
      },
      {
        "question": "Two trains cross each other in 14 seconds when running in opposite directions along parallel tracks. The faster train is 160 m long and crosses a lamp post in 12 seconds. If the speed of the other train is 6 km/hr less than the faster one, its length, in meters, is:",
        "options": ["190", "184", "180", "192"],
        "answer": "190"
      },
      {
        "question": "Onion is sold for 5 consecutive months at the rate of Rs 10, 20, 25, 25, and 50 per kg, respectively. A family spends a fixed amount of money on onion for each of the first three months, and then spends half that amount on onion for each of the next two months. The average expense for onion, in rupees per kg, for the family over these 5 months is closest to:",
        "options": ["26", "20", "16", "18"],
        "answer": "18"
      },
      {
        "question": "If the area of a regular hexagon is equal to the area of an equilateral triangle of side 12 cm, then the length, in cm, of each side of the hexagon is:",
        "options": ["6√6", "2√6", "√6", "4√6"],
        "answer": "2√6"
      },
      {
        "question": "The number of integers n that satisfy the inequalities |n - 60| < |n - 100| < |n - 20| is:",
        "options": ["18", "20", "19", "21"],
        "answer": "19"
      },
      {
        "question": "The amount Neeta and Geeta together earn in a day equals what Sita alone earns in 6 days. The amount Sita and Neeta together earn in a day equals what Geeta alone earns in 2 days. The ratio of the daily earnings of the one who earns the most to that of the one who earns the least is:",
        "options": ["11:7", "11:3", "7:3", "3:2"],
        "answer": "11:3"
      },
      {
        "question": "The natural numbers are divided into groups as (1), (2, 3, 4), (5, 6, 7, 8, 9), ..... and so on. Then, the sum of the numbers in the 15th group is equal to:",
        "options": ["6119", "4941", "6090", "7471"],
        "answer": "6119"
      },
      {
        "question": "Anil invests some money at a fixed rate of interest, compounded annually. If the interests accrued during the second and third year are 806.25 and 866.72, respectively, the interest accrued, in INR, during the fourth year is nearest to:",
        "options": ["934.65", "929.48", "926.84", "931.72"],
        "answer": "931.72"
      },
      {
        "question": "Anu, Vinu and Manu can complete a work alone in 15 days, 12 days and 20 days, respectively. Vinu works every day. Anu works only on alternate days starting from the first day while Manu works only on alternate days starting from the second day. Then, the number of days needed to complete the work is:",
        "options": ["6", "5", "8", "7"],
        "answer": "7"
      },
      
        {
          "question": "Two pipes A and B are attached to an empty water tank. Pipe A fills the tank while pipe B drains it. If pipe A is opened at 2 pm and pipe B is opened at 3 pm, then the tank becomes full at 10 pm. Instead, if pipe A is opened at 2 pm and pipe B is opened at 4 pm, then the tank becomes full at 6 pm. If pipe B is not opened at all, then the time, in minutes, taken to fill the tank is:",
          "options": ["144", "140", "264", "120"],
          "answer": "144"
        },
        {
          "question": "Anil, Bobby, and Chintu jointly invest in a business and agree to share the overall profit in proportion to their investments. Anil's share of investment is 70%. His share of profit decreases by 420 if the overall profit goes down from 18% to 15%. Chintu's share of profit increases by 80 if the overall profit goes up from 15% to 17%. The amount, in INR, invested by Bobby is:",
          "options": ["2000", "2400", "2200", "1800"],
          "answer": "2000"
        },
        {
          "question": "A person buys tea of three different qualities at 800, 500, and 300 per kg, respectively, and the amounts bought are in the proportion 2:3:5. She mixes all the tea and sells one-sixth of the mixture at 700 per kg. The price, in INR per kg, at which she should sell the remaining tea, to make an overall profit of 50%, is:",
          "options": ["653", "688", "692", "675"],
          "answer": "688"
        },
        {
          "question": "For a real number x the condition |3x-20| + |3x-40| = 20 necessarily holds if:",
          "options": ["10 < x < 15", "9 < x < 14", "7 < x < 12", "6 < x < 11"],
          "answer": "7 < x < 12"
        },
        {
          "question": "Anil can paint a house in 60 days while Bimal can paint it in 84 days. Anil starts painting and after 10 days, Bimal and Charu join him. Together, they complete the painting in 14 more days. If they are paid a total of 21000 for the job, then the share of Charu, in INR, proportionate to the work done by him, is:",
          "options": ["9000", "9200", "9100", "9150"],
          "answer": "9100"
        },
        {
          "question": "The sides AB and CD of a trapezium ABCD are parallel, with AB being the smaller side. P is the midpoint of CD and ABPD is a parallelogram. If the difference between the areas of the parallelogram ABPD and the triangle BPC is 10 sq cm, then the area, in sq cm, of the trapezium ABCD is:",
          "options": ["30", "40", "25", "20"],
          "answer": "30"
        },
        {
          "question": "Bank A offers 6% interest rate per annum compounded half yearly. Bank B and Bank C offer simple interest but the annual interest rate offered by Bank C is twice that of Bank B. Raju invests a certain amount in Bank B for a certain period and Rupa invests 10,000 in Bank C for twice that period. The interest that would accrue to Raju during that period is equal to the interest that would have accrued had he invested the same amount in Bank A for one year. The interest accrued, in INR, to Rupa is:",
          "options": ["1.1436", "2.2436", "3.3436", "4.2346"],
          "answer": "3.3436"
        },
        {
          "question": "If f(x) = x² - 7x and g(x) = x + 3, then the minimum value of f(g(x)) - 3x is:",
          "options": ["-15", "-20", "-16", "-12"],
          "answer": "-16"
        },
        {
          "question": "In a tournament, a team has played 40 matches so far and won 30% of them. If they win 60% of the remaining matches, their overall win percentage will be 50%. Suppose they win 90% of the remaining matches, then the total number of matches won by the team in the tournament will be:",
          "options": ["86", "78", "80", "84"],
          "answer": "84"
        },
        {
          "question": "A shop owner bought a total of 64 shirts from a wholesale market that came in two sizes, small and large. The price of a small shirt was INR 50 less than that of a large shirt. She paid a total of INR 5000 for the large shirts, and a total of INR 1800 for the small shirts. Then, the price of a large shirt and a small shirt together, in INR, is:",
          "options": ["200", "175", "225", "150"],
          "answer": "200"
        },
        {
          "question": "If a certain weight of an alloy of silver and copper is mixed with 3 kg of pure silver, the resulting alloy will have 90% silver by weight. If the same weight of the initial alloy is mixed with 2 kg of another alloy which has 90% silver by weight, the resulting alloy will have 84% silver by weight. Then, the weight of the initial alloy, in kg, is:",
          "options": ["3.5", "4", "3", "2.5"],
          "answer": "3"
        },
       
            {
              "question": "A journal plans to publish 18 research papers, written by eight authors (A, B, C, D, E, F, G, and H) in four issues of the journal scheduled in January, April, July, and October. Each of the research papers was written by exactly one of the eight authors. Five papers were scheduled in each of the first two issues, while four were scheduled in each of the last two issues. Every author wrote at least one paper and at most three papers. The total number of papers written by A, D, G, and H was double the total number of papers written by the other four authors. Four of the authors were from India and two each were from Japan and China. Each author belonged to exactly one of the three areas — Manufacturing, Automation, and Logistics. Four of the authors were from the Logistics area and two were from the Automation area. As per the journal policy, none of the authors could have more than one paper in any issue of the journal. Based on this, what is the correct sequence of number of papers written by B, C, E, and G, respectively?",
              "options": [
                "3, 1, 1, 3",
                "1, 2, 2, 1",
                "1, 2, 2, 3",
                "1, 3, 3, 1"
              ],
              "answer": "1, 2, 2, 3"
              
            },
          
            {
              "question": "A journal plans to publish 18 research papers, written by eight authors (A, B, C, D, E, F, G, and H) in four issues of the journal scheduled in January, April, July, and October. Each of the research papers was written by exactly one of the eight authors. Five papers were scheduled in each of the first two issues, while four were scheduled in each of the last two issues. Every author wrote at least one paper and at most three papers. The total number of papers written by A, D, G, and H was double the total number of papers written by the other four authors. Four of the authors were from India and two each were from Japan and China. Each author belonged to exactly one of the three areas — Manufacturing, Automation, and Logistics. Four of the authors were from the Logistics area and two were from the Automation area. As per the journal policy, none of the authors could have more than one paper in any issue of the journal. Based on this, which of the following statement(s) MUST be true?",
              "options": [
                "Only Statement A",
                "Neither of the statements",
                "Both the statements",
                "Only Statement B"
              ],
              "answer": "Only Statement A"
             
            },
            {
              "question": "A journal plans to publish 18 research papers, written by eight authors (A, B, C, D, E, F, G, and H) in four issues of the journal scheduled in January, April, July, and October. Each of the research papers was written by exactly one of the eight authors. Five papers were scheduled in each of the first two issues, while four were scheduled in each of the last two issues. Every author wrote at least one paper and at most three papers. The total number of papers written by A, D, G, and H was double the total number of papers written by the other four authors. Four of the authors were from India and two each were from Japan and China. Each author belonged to exactly one of the three areas — Manufacturing, Automation, and Logistics. Four of the authors were from the Logistics area and two were from the Automation area. As per the journal policy, none of the authors could have more than one paper in any issue of the journal. Based on this, which of the following statements is FALSE?",
              "options": [
                "Every issue had exactly one paper by a Chinese author.",
                "Every issue had at least one paper by author(s) from Automation area.",
                "Every issue had exactly two papers by authors from Logistics area.",
                "Every issue had exactly two papers by Indian authors."
              ],
              "answer": "Every issue had exactly two papers by authors from Logistics area.."
              
            },
            {
              "question": "A journal plans to publish 18 research papers, written by eight authors (A, B, C, D, E, F, G, and H) in four issues of the journal scheduled in January, April, July, and October. Each of the research papers was written by exactly one of the eight authors. Five papers were scheduled in each of the first two issues, while four were scheduled in each of the last two issues. Every author wrote at least one paper and at most three papers. The total number of papers written by A, D, G, and H was double the total number of papers written by the other four authors. Four of the authors were from India and two each were from Japan and China. Each author belonged to exactly one of the three areas — Manufacturing, Automation, and Logistics. Four of the authors were from the Logistics area and two were from the Automation area. As per the journal policy, none of the authors could have more than one paper in any issue of the journal. Based on this, which of the following statements is FALSE?",
              "options": [
                "There was exactly one paper by an author from Logistics area in the October issue.",
                "There was exactly one paper by an author from Manufacturing area in the April issue.",
                "There were exactly two papers by authors from Manufacturing area in the July issue.",
                "There were exactly two papers by authors from Manufacturing area in the January issue."
              ],
              "answer": "There were exactly two papers by authors from Manufacturing area in the July issue."
             
            },
            {
              "question": "A journal plans to publish 18 research papers, written by eight authors (A, B, C, D, E, F, G, and H) in four issues of the journal scheduled in January, April, July, and October. Each of the research papers was written by exactly one of the eight authors. Five papers were scheduled in each of the first two issues, while four were scheduled in each of the last two issues. Every author wrote at least one paper and at most three papers. The total number of papers written by A, D, G, and H was double the total number of papers written by the other four authors. Four of the authors were from India and two each were from Japan and China. Each author belonged to exactly one of the three areas — Manufacturing, Automation, and Logistics. Four of the authors were from the Logistics area and two were from the Automation area. As per the journal policy, none of the authors could have more than one paper in any issue of the journal. Based on this, which of the following is the correct sequence of number of papers by authors from Automation, Manufacturing, and Logistics areas, respectively?",
              "options": [
                "6, 5, 7",
                "6, 7, 5",
                "5, 6, 7",
                "6, 6, 6"
              ],
              "answer": "6, 5, 7"
              
            },
            
                {
                  "question": "In the game of Chango, 12 players participated in a Chango championship. They were divided into four groups: Group A consisted of Aruna, Azul, and Arif; Group B consisted of Brinda, Brij, and Biju; Group C consisted of Chitra, Chetan, and Chhavi; and Group D consisted of Dipen, Donna, and Deb. Players within each group had a distinct rank going into the championship. The players have NOT been listed necessarily according to their ranks. In the group stage of the game, the second and third ranked players play against each other, and the winner of that game plays against the first ranked player of the group. The winner of this second game is considered as the winner of the group and enters a semi-final. The winners from Groups A and B play against each other in one semi-final, while the winners from Groups C and D play against each other in the other semi-final. The winners of the two semi-finals play against each other in the final to decide the winner of the championship. Who among the following was DEFINITELY NOT ranked first in his/her group?",
                  "options": [
                    "Chitra",
                    "Aruna",
                    "Dipen",
                    "Brij"
                  ],
                  "answer": "Dipen"
                 
                },
                {
                  "question": "In the game of Chango, 12 players participated in a Chango championship. They were divided into four groups: Group A consisted of Aruna, Azul, and Arif; Group B consisted of Brinda, Brij, and Biju; Group C consisted of Chitra, Chetan, and Chhavi; and Group D consisted of Dipen, Donna, and Deb. Players within each group had a distinct rank going into the championship. The players have NOT been listed necessarily according to their ranks. In the group stage of the game, the second and third ranked players play against each other, and the winner of that game plays against the first ranked player of the group. The winner of this second game is considered as the winner of the group and enters a semi-final. The winners from Groups A and B play against each other in one semi-final, while the winners from Groups C and D play against each other in the other semi-final. The winners of the two semi-finals play against each other in the final to decide the winner of the championship. Which of the following pairs must have played against each other in the championship?",
                  "options": [
                    "Azul, Biju",
                    "Donna, Chetan",
                    "Deb, Donna",
                    "Chitra, Dipen"
                  ],
                  "answer": "Chitra, Dipen"
                 
                },
                {
                  "question": "In the game of Chango, 12 players participated in a Chango championship. They were divided into four groups: Group A consisted of Aruna, Azul, and Arif; Group B consisted of Brinda, Brij, and Biju; Group C consisted of Chitra, Chetan, and Chhavi; and Group D consisted of Dipen, Donna, and Deb. Players within each group had a distinct rank going into the championship. The players have NOT been listed necessarily according to their ranks. In the group stage of the game, the second and third ranked players play against each other, and the winner of that game plays against the first ranked player of the group. The winner of this second game is considered as the winner of the group and enters a semi-final. The winners from Groups A and B play against each other in one semi-final, while the winners from Groups C and D play against each other in the other semi-final. The winners of the two semi-finals play against each other in the final to decide the winner of the championship. Who won the championship?",
                  "options": [
                    "Brij",
                    "Chitra",
                    "Cannot be determined",
                    "Aruna"
                  ],
                  "answer": "Aruna"
                 
                },
                {
                  "question": "In the game of Chango, 12 players participated in a Chango championship. They were divided into four groups: Group A consisted of Aruna, Azul, and Arif; Group B consisted of Brinda, Brij, and Biju; Group C consisted of Chitra, Chetan, and Chhavi; and Group D consisted of Dipen, Donna, and Deb. Players within each group had a distinct rank going into the championship. The players have NOT been listed necessarily according to their ranks. In the group stage of the game, the second and third ranked players play against each other, and the winner of that game plays against the first ranked player of the group. The winner of this second game is considered as the winner of the group and enters a semi-final. The winners from Groups A and B play against each other in one semi-final, while the winners from Groups C and D play against each other in the other semi-final. The winners of the two semi-finals play against each other in the final to decide the winner of the championship. Who among the following did NOT play against Chitra in the championship?",
                  "options": [
                    "Aruna",
                    "Dipen",
                    "Chetan",
                    "Biju"
                  ],
                  "answer": "Biju"
                 
                }
              ]
            }
            
          
        
      
      
    
  
  